

Javier Mauricio Pinilla Garcia

CONTACT

Nationality: Colombian

Gender: Male

Bogota, Colombia

ing.jmpinillag@gmail.com

(+49) 1782337666 https://github.com/

ingjavierpinilla

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ ingjavierpinilla/

Whatsapp Messenger: +49

1782337666

ABOUT ME

Software developer with 2 years of experience and a bachelor's degree in mechatronics engineering. I have successfully worked on projects of consumer application development, data processing, cloud services and web development in both large companies and start-ups. I have experience working remotely in positions spoken entirely in English and German

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/08/2020 - 31/10/2020 - Bogota, Colombia

Data analyst

Freelance

Development of web application for the visualization and data manipulation.

Creation of a machine learning model to predict the total number of hours it will take to develop a software project in order to estimate costs at the beginning of the project.

Languages and technologies used: Python, Dash, Postgresql, Scikit-learn, AWS, S3, EC2

16/03/2020 - 14/09/2020 - Stuttgart, Germany

Software Engineer / Full Time Intern

Robert Bosch GmbH

- Development of software for the reception, decoding, and storage in HDF5 format of the data coming from the sensors of autonomously driven vehicles using C++.
- Create software for reading and displaying the vehicle's sensors onboard the vehicle.
- Create application to automate ECU flashing using python (ironpython and WPF) and PRACTICE
- Web scraping with python and beautifulsoup.

Languages and technologies used: Python, Iron Python, C++, WPF, Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, HDF5, PRACTICE, SQL, Git

01/03/2019 - 31/08/2019 - Bogota, Colombia

Software Engineer

Bsmart EU

Development of a license plate recognition system, as well as support to different projects focused on the area of machine learning applied to images.

Languages and technologies used: Python, OpenCV, C++, MySQL

05/02/2018 - 04/02/2019 - Bogotá, Colombia

Software Engineer

Freelance

Development of an own product.

Automatic license plate recognition system developed using python together with opency where through the use of neural networks the number of colombian license plates could be obtained as a text string.

Languages and technologies used: Python, OpenCV, MySQL, AWS

15/08/2018 - 15/12/2018 - Bogota, Colombia

Assistant teacher

Universidad Nacional de Colombia

- Collaborate with the teacher to write laboratory practices and assessments
- Design and make PCBs of some electronic devices used in the laboratory

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

19/01/2015 - 18/12/2020 - Bogota, Colombia

Mechatronics Bachelor's Degree

Universidad Nacional de Colombia

https://unal.edu.co

30/08/2020 - 13/11/2020 - Colombia

Data scientists, Data Science For All

Correlation One

https://www.correlation-one.com/ds4a-latam

01/10/2019 - 07/10/2020 - Keplerstraße 7, Stuttgart, Germany

Academic exchange year

Stuttgart Universität

I had the opportunity to attend classes related to robotics and data processing of the mechatronics master. In addition, I did an internship as a student at Robert Bosch GmbH

Field(s) of study

Engineering, manufacturing and construction

https://www.uni-stuttgart.de

LANGUAGE SKILLS

MOTHER TONGUE(S): Spanish

OTHER LANGUAGE(S):

English

Listening C1	Reading C1	Spoken production C1	Spoken interaction C1	Writing C1
German	Reading	Spoken	Spoken	Writing
B2	B2	production B2	interaction B2	B2

DIGITAL SKILLS

python / git / GIT (GitHub) / Java Programming language / C, C++c C# / SQL/MYSQL / Machine Learning libraries Scikit-Learn Tensorflow Keras Scipy / AWS EC2 RDS S3 Lambda / Django Framework & Django REST / ReactJS / C#, WPF, WCF, SQL